swissarmy.com 2016-04-14

# Privacy Policy | Victorinox Swiss Army

Victorinox Swiss Army, Inc. (“VSAI”, “We” or “Us”) respects the privacy concerns of our website users and customers and has set forth this Privacy Policy to clearly explain to you how we collect and use your information. This Privacy Policy is only applicable for communications to the United States, Canada for the website located at www.swissarmy.com and www.victorinox.com (the "Website"). Though our trademark might appear on other websites, such other websites have their own policies and are not subject to this policy.

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

**Information that we collect**

VSAI and our affiliates and licensees which include, but may not be limited to TRG Accessories, L.L.C., Victorinox Retail and Victorinox Global Fashion, Inc. value our customers and respect your privacy.

**Personally Identifiable Information**

We only collect personally identifiable information from you when you voluntarily provide it to us, such as by registering on the Website for an account, purchasing a product online, in one of our stores, uploading content to the Website (such as posting comments), completing an online contact request form on the Website or otherwise choosing to share your personally identifiable information with us. The personally identifiable information which you may provide to us could include your name, email address, physical address, phone number, date of birth, credit card number and other personal information.

We use this information to contact you to respond to your inquiry, provide you with certain services and access, and as otherwise permitted by this Privacy Policy. If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence. If you choose to submit content to any public area of the Website including a publicly accessible blog or a social media platform (including without limitation by giving us consent to post your content to any public areas of the Website, or in any other manner permitted by the Website), such content will be considered “public” and will not be subject to the privacy protections set forth herein. We are unable to control such uses of your personally identifiable information, and by using such services you assume the risk that the personally identifiable information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties for any number of purposes

When you choose to connect your social media account to the Website, or otherwise access the Website via a third party service, we may collect personally identifiable information from that social media platform and/or service, and you give us permission to access and use information, content, and/or material you have supplied to that service as permitted by that social media platform and/or service. For example, when you connect your Twitter, or Facebook account to register for the Website, we may collect the personally identifiable information you have made publicly available in those accounts in your profile, such as your name, photograph, headline, contact information, experience, education, summary, and location. We may also obtain other non-public information from the social media account with your permission. You understand that you are responsible for the content posted as part of your profile information. In addition, you understand that certain categories of information such as your user name and profile photo are publicly available to other users and us, and therefore will not be kept confidential.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

When you access our Website, we may also automatically collect non-personally identifiable information from you, such as IP type, IP host address, ISP address, cookie IDs, segment IDs associated with cookie IDs, web pages viewed and/or search terms entered, browser type, operating system, referring website, usage and browsing habits on the Website, anonymous usage statistics including frequency of messaging and interaction with other users, clickstream data other log file data, or social analytics and tracking measurements that do not identify any individual. On mobile devices, we may also collect device type, make and model, operating system, carrier, user ID, similar device IDs, and information about the apps you use. Please note that we may use third party service providers to help operate and provide services in connection with our Website and these third party service providers will collect non-personally identifiable information from our Website as well. We may also aggregate demographic information collected from our users (such as the number of users in a particular State) in a manner which does not identify any one individual. Please note that we use third party service providers to help operate and provide services in connection with our Website (including Interest-Based Advertising as discussed below) and these third party service providers will collect non-personally identifiable information from our Website as well.

**Cookies**

We may also collect non-personally identifiable information through the use of cookies and similar tracking methods. Cookies are tools used to retrieve information during your online session, such as keeping track of the items placed in your shopping cart. We and each of our business partners may use cookies (or clear gifs, web beacons or similar devices, including devices that function in the mobile environment) to collect information from you for purposes such as tracking Website visits and to measure visitor patterns. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for up to one (1) year. We set a persistent cookie to enable us to track and target the interests of users to enhance the services we provide. Such cookies may store personally identifiable information on your local computer to make it easier for you to use our Website. Many web browsers are designed to accept cookies, but you may prefer to modify your browser to prevent acceptance. It is possible, however, that some areas of this Website will not function properly if you do so. You may stop or restrict the placement of cookies on your computer or flush them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences, in which case you may still use our Website, but it may interfere with some of its functionality. Cookies and similar items are not used by us to automatically retrieve personally identifiable information from your computer without your knowledge.   
_**Third parties may also use cookies to track your behavior on our Website and on third-party websites, in order to deliver targeted advertising to you. To learn more about this practice and your choices with respect to it, please visit**_ <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

**Tracking Links Clicked/Clickstream**

In order to create a better electronic community, we may keep track of patterns of use in the emails we send out. We note which links are clicked in our email communications as specific user profile information to tell us what areas are of most interest to our opt-in email recipients. We may use this information to better personalize the content and promotions that visitors and mail recipients will see in our mailings.

Additionally, we collect a trail of electronic information that you leave each time you visit the Website. This information, which is sometimes referred to as "clickstream data," can be collected and stored by a website’s server. Clickstream data can tell us the type of computer and browsing software you use and the address of the website from which you linked to the Website. We may collect and/or use clickstream data to anonymously determine how much time visitors spend on each page of the Website, how visitors navigate throughout the Website and how the Website may be better tailored to meet the needs of visitors. This information will be used to improve the Site and services. Any collection or use of clickstream data will be anonymous, and will not contain any personally identifiable information.

**Information Usage**

We will only use your personally identifiable information as described below, unless you have specifically consented to another type of use, either at the time the personally identifiable information is collected from you or through some other form of consent from you or notification to you:

  * We may use your personally identifiable information to respond to your inquiries or requests.
  * Your personally identifiable information will be used and shared with our business partners to process your purchases, such as by credit card processors and shipping companies.
  * We may use your personally identifiable information to send you emails from time to time about our products if you have opted into our mailing lists, but we will not provide your personally identifiable information to third parties for them to contact you directly unless otherwise permitted by this Privacy Policy or you provide your consent.
  * If you have opted in to our mailing lists, we may share your information among our affiliates and licensees in an effort to improve your shopping experience and to permit them to communicate with you about products, services, promotions and contests in which you might be interested. See the section entitled “Opt-Out Process,” below, for instructions on how you may opt out of such sharing.
  * We may permit our vendors and subcontractors to access your personally identifiable information, but they are only permitted to do so in connection with performing services for us. They are not authorized by us to use the information for their own benefit.
  * We may disclose personally identifiable information as required by law or legal process.
  * We may disclose personally identifiable information to investigate suspected fraud, harassment or other violations of any law, rule or regulation, or the terms or policies for our Website.
  * We may transfer your personally identifiable information in connection with the sale or merger or change of control of VSAI or the division responsible for the services with which your personally identifiable information is associated.

Non- personally identifiable or aggregate information may be shared with any number of parties, provided that such information shall not specifically identify you.

**Interest-Based Advertising**

We may ourselves, or with third party vendors, use non-personally identifiable information in connection with our own or vendor information to deliver targeted advertising to you when you visit other websites or our Website. Cookies, clickstream data, and other similar technologies described above may be used in this process. For example, if you are searching for information on a particular product, we or our vendor may cause an advertisement to appear on other websites you view with information on that product. This form of advertising, sometimes called “behavioral advertising,” is based on anonymous information and not on any personally identifiable information. As a result, we and our vendor know your interests, but cannot personally identify you in connection with the delivery of that specific ad. We believe that such advertising is helpful because you will see advertisements that are relevant to your interests. However, if you would like to opt-out of these interest-based advertisements, please follow the opt-out process described below under “Opt-Out.”

**Security**

The security of your personally identifiable information is very important to us. When we collect your personally identifiable information offline, we use commercially reasonable efforts to protect it from unauthorized access. We use a safe and secure online ordering system. We use industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology for online purchases. This secure server software encrypts all of your personally identifiable information during a purchase, including credit card number, address, first and last name, so that it cannot be easily read in transfer. However, due to the inherent open nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that your personally identifiable information will be completely free from unauthorized access by third parties such as hackers and your use of our Website demonstrates your assumption of this risk. We may retain your personally identifiable information, if provided by you through the Website, for as long as your inquiry is active (as determined by us) and for a reasonable time thereafter, or if applicable, for as long as you remain on our marketing list. We also may retain your personally identifiable information for a longer period of time as needed to provide you services or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements. Even if we delete some or all of your personally identifiable information, we may continue to retain and use aggregate, anonymous data previously collected and/or anonymize and aggregate your personal information. Please note that we will not be liable for disclosures of your data due to errors or unauthorized acts of third parties, including third party host providers. We may aggregate non- personally identifiable information and retain it for analytical purposes.

**Protection for Children**

Our Website is designed for those 18 years of age and older. We do not intentionally collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18. When we become aware that personal information from a child under 18 has been collected without such child’s parent or guardian’s consent, we will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this Privacy Policy at any time. However, if at any time in the future we plan to use personally identifiable information in a way that materially differs from this Privacy Policy, including sharing such information with more third parties, we will post such changes here and provide you the opportunity to opt-out of such differing uses. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of any changes to this Privacy Policy means you accept such changes.

**Data retention**

We retain your information for as long as we reasonably believe that there is a commercial reason for doing so.

**Opt-Out Process**

As noted above, you may stop or restrict the placement of cookies on your computer or remove them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences. Please note that cookie-based opt-outs are not effective on mobile applications.

In addition, you may restrict the placement of cookies or opt out of Interest-Based Advertising that is served through a web browser by setting a cookie which tells our systems to ignore you and not display targeted ads. To opt out of such advertising, click here: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. Please note that by opting out, you will continue to see generic advertising that is not tailored to your specific interests and activities. If you choose to opt out using our opt-out tool, we will add a cookie to your browser identifying it as an opted-out browser. Once you have elected to opt-out and our system has refreshed (which may take up to twenty-four hours), our advertising system will not collect or use any behavioral data associated with your browser for targeted advertising services for so long as our opt-out cookie remains in place.

**To be clear, whether you are using our opt-out or an online industry opt-out, these cookie-based opt-outs must be performed on each device and browser that you wish to have opted-out.** For example, if you have opted out on your computer browser, that opt-out will not be effective on your mobile device. You must separately opt out on each device.

To opt out of receiving email marketing from us and from our sharing of your information with our affiliates and licensees for their own direct marketing purposes, please send your request to us at [unsubscribe@swsissarmy.com](mailto:unsubscribe@swsissarmy.com). If you have consented to have your personally identifiable information shared with any third party who may use such information for direct marketing purposes and you no longer wish to have your PII shared with such parties, then you may opt-out of such disclosures by sending an email to email address provided above. However, we are not responsible for removing your personally identifiable information from the lists of any third party who has previously been provided your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy or your consent, such as a third party company selling products to you through the Website. You should contact such third parties directly.

Please note that there might be a brief delay between when you submit your request to “opt-out” and when it is processed and reflected in our systems. We will seek to process your request within a reasonable time after receipt; accordingly you may continue to receive communications from us for a limited time after you opt-out/unsubscribe. We appreciate your patience.

**Links to Third Party Sites and Social Media Platforms**

The Website or advertisements we place may contain links to other websites or applications. Other websites or applications may also reference or link to our Website. Some of our third-party website or technology partners may place their own cookies and/or other data collection tools on your Internet browser; however, we have no access to or control over these cookies and/or other data collection tools. These other domains, websites and/or apps are not controlled by us. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of each and every website and application that you interact with. We do not endorse, screen or approve, and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other websites or applications. Visiting these other websites or applications is at your own risk.

Our Website may also contain links to social media platforms, and you may be given the choice of connecting to one or more social media platforms from this Website. If you choose to do so, then depending upon your social media privacy settings, the personal information that you post, transmit, or otherwise make available on the social media platform may be viewed and/or used by others and we will have no control over such viewing and use. We do not control and are not responsible for any use of your information by or through any of the social media platforms. By linking to any social media platform, you will be assuming the risk that the information you provide on that platform may be viewed and/or used by third parties for any purposes and agree that we have no control or responsibility for such third party viewing and uses.

**Communications with Victorinox**

By providing your email address to us, you expressly consent to receive emails from us. We may use email to communicate with you, to send information that you have requested or to send information about other products or services developed or provided by us or our business partners, or to verify your account, and for information, website functionality and operational purposes, provided that, we will not give your email address to another party to promote their products or services directly to you without your consent or as set forth in this policy. If you receive an email from us, in addition to the opt-out procedure outlined above, you may unsubscribe from receiving future unsolicited emails through a link, typically at the bottom of the e-mail.

**Terms of Use and Governing Law**

Use of this Website is governed by, and subject to, the Terms of Use. **If you do not agree to these Terms of Use you may not access or otherwise use this Website.**

**This Privacy Policy and our legal obligations hereunder are governed by, and subject to, the laws of the State of Connecticut. You hereby expressly consent to exclusive jurisdiction and venue in the courts located in Fairfield county, Connecticut for all matters arising in connection with this Privacy Policy.**

**Information Storage**

Our servers are maintained in Switzerland. By using the Website or making a purchase, you freely and specifically give us your consent to export your personally identifiable information to Switzerland and to store and use it in Switzerland as specified in this Privacy Policy. Our overseas hosting provider is contractually authorized to use your personally identifiable information only as necessary to provide services to us and use reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect against unauthorized access.

We comply with U.S.-E.U. and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the European Union and Switzerland. To learn more about the Safe Harbor programs principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

**Addressing Questions, Concerns and Complaints**

For any questions, concerns or complaints relating to this Privacy Policy or our collection, use and disclosure of personally identifiable information, we can be contacted at the email or address provided below. You may also request to access your personally identifiable information (if you have provided personally identifiable information to us through the Website). Subject to certain restrictions/exceptions prescribed by law, we will grant reasonable access to your personally identifiable information, and the ability to have it amended as appropriate.

Via email: [consumer.inquiries@swissarmy.com](mailto:consumer.inquiries@swissarmy.com?subject=Privacy) RE: Privacy   
Via regular mail: [ADDRESS], [CONTACT PERSON]

Last updated September 1, 2015
